The journey into excess starts with a moustache.
Dalíland is a history, drama film directed by Mary Harron.
In 1973, a young gallery assistant goes on a wild adventure behind the scenes as he
helps aging genius Salvador Dali prepare for a big show in New York.
Dalí, played by Ben Kingsley.
Gala, played by Barbara Sukowa.
James, played by Christopher Briney.
Captain Moore, played by Rupert Graves.
Amanda, played by Andreja Pejić.
Ginesta, played by Suki Waterhouse.
Dalíland is a 2022 American biographical film directed by Mary Harron.
It is based on the true story of the painter Salvador Dalí and his
tempestuous marriage to muse and wife Gala during the 1970s.
The film stars Ben Kingsley, Barbara Sukowa, Christopher Briney, Rupert Graves,
Alexander Beyer, Andreja Pejić, Suki Waterhouse, and Ezra Miller.
Dalíland had its world premiere at the Toronto International Film Festival on September 17,
2022 and was released in the United States on June 9, 2023 by Magnolia Pictures.
The tone is emotional.